A Guide to the Office of the Messrs. Rockefeller records, John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Personal, Series Z FA335
Rockefeller Archive Center
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Personal Papers, 1878-1960, 1974; 2; 35 Document Box(es)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip, 1929 January-March
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - Purchases, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 374)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Correspondence - Young Men's Christian Association, Cairo, 1928-1929 (Box 42, Folder 375)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Diary, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 376)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Itineraries, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 377)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Letters to Children and John D. Rockefeller, Sr., 1929 (Box 42, Folder 378)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Photograph of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1929 (Box 42, Folder 379)
    - Travel Records, Foreign - Egypt Trip - Printed Material, 1929 (Box 42, Folder 380)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - France (October-November 1930) - Correspondence (Box 42, Folder 381)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller to Paris. Motored to Spain. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - Italy, 1934-1935 (Box 42, Folder 382)
    With Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Visited Italy and Capri. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - France (July 1936) - General Information (Box 42, Folder 383)
  - Travel Records, Foreign - France (July 1936) - Statements on Repeal of Prohibition (Box 42, Folder 384)
    Statements made following 1936 trip.
  - Travel Records, Foreign - England and France (May-July 1938) - Address Book and Correspondence (Box 42, Folder 385)
    With Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Headquarters in Paris. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Travel Records, United States - Yellowstone Park - Diary, 1886 (Box 42, Folder 386)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. traveled with his family.
  - Travel Records, United States, 1899, 1903 (Box 42, Folder 387)
    California and Alaska, 1899. Itinerary. Mexico and California, 1903. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Diary.
  - Travel Records, United States - Diaries, 1904, 1906 (Box 42, Folder 388)
    Berkshires, 1904. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Berkshires, 1906. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Percy Rockefeller. White Mountains (New Hampshire), 1906. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Percy Rockefeller.
  - Travel Records, United States - Western Trip (May-August 1920) - Correspondence (Box 42, Folder 389)
    Took Abby Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller on birds-eye view of the west. Colorado, California, Pacific Northwest planned. Children got the measles in Colorado. Party quarantined for ten days. Shortened trip. Visited Hollywood, Canadian Rockies. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. objects to newspaper accounts of gymnasium on trains which was untrue. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Charles O. Heydt.
  - Travel Records, United States - Western Trip (May-August 1920) - Correspondence (Box 42, Folder 390)
  - Travel Records, United States - Western Trip (May-August 1920) - Diary (Box 43, Folder 391)
  - Travel Records, United States - Glacier National Park (June-August 1924)
    Trip to Grand Canyon, Mesa Verda, Glacier and Yellowstone National Parks. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. took three older boys. Gifts to various acquaintances on trip. Preparations. Met Jessie Nusbaum on this trip.
    - Correspondence, 1924-1926 (Box 43, Folder 392)
    - Correspondence - Hotels, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 393)
    - Correspondence - McClintock, Walter, 1924, 1928 (Box 43, Folder 394)
      McClintock was Indian specialist who went along. Indian appeal for help.
    - Correspondence - Purchases, 1924-1925 (Box 43, Folder 395)
      Gifts to Indians, guides, etc.
    - Correspondence - Ralston, H., 1924-1925, 1932 (Box 43, Folder 396)
      Ralston was guide on camping trip in Glacier National Park. Gift to guide and others.
    - Correspondence - Tillett, William S., 1924 (Box 43, Folder 397)
      Tillet was doctor who accompanied.
    - Correspondence - Wiswall, W. W., 1924-1925 (Box 43, Folder 398)
      Purchase of Indian blankets and pottery.
    - Diary, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 399)
      Glacier Park Pack Train.
    - Itineraries, 1924 (Box 43, Folder 400)
  - Travel Records, United States - Florida - Correspondence, 1925 (Box 43, Folder 401)
    Ormond, St. Augustine, Miami, West Palm Beach. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller, Sr.
  - Travel Records, United States - Hot Springs, Virginia - Correspondence, 1925-1926 (Box 43, Folder 402)
    Gettysburg, 1925. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, David Rockefeller.
  - Travel Records, United States - Hampton, Virginia - Correspondence, 1926-1927 (Box 43, Folder 403)
    Hampton, Williamsburg, Richmond, 1926. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Nelson A. Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller and David Rockefeller. Hampton Institute trip. Visited Williamsburg for the first time.
  - Travel Records, United States - Western Trip (June-July 1926)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, and three sons visited Yosemite, California coast, Redwood Country. Private car. "Boston" and "Advance" visited Jackson Hole.
    - Correspondence, January-May 1926 (Box 43, Folder 404)
    - Correspondence, June 1926-March 1928 (Box 43, Folder 405)
    - Correspondence - Purchases, 1926, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 406)
      Purchases of pottery, rugs.
    - Correspondence - Purchases, 1926, 1960 (Box 44, Folder 0406A)
      Purchase of pottery, rugs.
    - Correspondence - Railroad Arrangements, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 407)
      Cost for railroad portion of trip.
    - Diary, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 408)
    - Itineraries and Memoranda, 1926 (Box 44, Folder 409)
      Memos by Robert W. Gumbel regarding itinerary and expenses.
    - Printed Material, 1926, n.d. (Box 44, Folder 410)
  - Travel Records, United States - Atlanta - Correspondence, 1927 (Box 44, Folder 411)
    Atlanta, Richmond, Williamsburg. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Spelman Trip, to dedicate Sisters Chapel at Spelman College.
  - Travel Records, United States - Great Lakes (June-July 1928) - Correspondence (Box 44, Folder 412)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, Misses French, John D. Rockefeller 3rd, Nelson A. Rockefeller, David Rockefeller, Laurance S. Rockefeller, Winthrop Rockefeller, Mr. Alton. Steamer Niagara, Detroit, Mackinac, Duluth, Hibbing. Steamer trip to Mesabi.
  - Travel Records, United States - Asheville, North Carolina - Correspondence, 1928-1929 (Box 44, Folder 413)
    Grove Park, North Carolina, 1928. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller rest trip.
  - Travel Records, United States - Western Trip (June-August 1930)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Abby Aldrich Rockefeller, and three boys. John D. Rockefeller 3rd planned trip to Santa Fe, Yellowstone and Glacier Parks. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. gives money to aid ranch in financial trouble. Other appeals for similar aid declined. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
    - Correspondence, January-June 1930 (Box 44, Folder 414)
    - Correspondence, July-December 1930 (Box 44, Folder 415)
    - Correspondence, 1931-1933, 1935 (Box 44, Folder 416)
    - Itineraries, 1930 (Box 44, Folder 417)
    - Printed Material, 1930 (Box 44, Folder 418)
  - Travel Records, United States - Western Trip (October 1931) - Correspondence (Box 44, Folder 419)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller visit Jackson Hole in October 1931. Picture of John D. Rockefeller, Jr. on horseback. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Travel Records, United States - Hot Springs, Virginia - Correspondence, 1932-1933 (Box 45, Folder 420)
    Washington, Hot Springs, Shenandoah, 1932. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller. Hot Springs, 1933. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller.
  - Travel Records, United States - Hot Springs, Virginia - Maps and Memoranda, 1914-1932 (Box 45, Folder 421)
  - Travel Records, United States - Hot Springs, Virginia - "The Homestead" - Correspondence, 1915-1957 (Box 45, Folder 422)
  - Travel Records, United States - Hot Springs Valley Nursing Association, 1916-1948 (Box 45, Folder 423)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. contributions toward Hot Springs, Community House and Hospital, and local churches.
  - Travel Records, United States - "Motor Trip in the South" - Diary, 1934 (Box 45, Folder 424)
  - Travel Records, United States - Arizona - Correspondence, 1946-1948 (Box 45, Folder 425)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. and Abby Aldrich Rockefeller traveled to Arizona, 1947. Arrangements. Letters to railroad men thanking them for their services. Friends invitations in Tucson. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. M. Warfield, R. Norris, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Travel Records, United States - Jackson Hole, Wyoming - Correspondence, 1946-1951, 1953 (Box 45, Folder 426)
    Itineraries of trips to Jackson Hole and JY Ranch, 1947, 1949, 1950, 1951, 1953.
  - Travel Records, United States - Great Smoky Mountains - Correspondence, 1950, 1954 (Box 45, Folder 427)
    John D. Rockefeller, Jr. traveled with David Rockefeller, 1950. John D. Rockefeller, Jr. traveled with Martha Baird Rockefeller, 1954.
  - Travel Records, United States - Arizona - Correspondence, 1951-1952 (Box 45, Folder 428)
    Arrangements. Letters to railroad men thanking them for their services. Friends invitations in Tucson. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., J. M. Warfield, R. Norris, Robert W. Gumbel.
  - Travel Records, United States - Arizona - Correspondence, 1953-1955 (Box 45, Folder 429)
  - Travel Records, United States - Arizona - Correspondence, 1956-1957 (Box 45, Folder 430)
  - Travel Records, United States - Arizona - Correspondence, 1958-1960 (Box 45, Folder 431)
  - Travel Records, United States - Tucson, Arizona - Correspondence, 1959 (Box 45, Folder 432)
  - Travel Records, United States - Miscellaneous Papers, 1889-1940, n.d. (Box 45, Folder 433)
  - Family Menu Cards, 1911-1917 (Box 79, Folder 0433A)
  - Gifts to Family Trusts - Outright Gifts, 1916-1957 (Box 80, Folder 433B)
    Conditions Governing Access note
    Restricted material.
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Benevolence Records, 1925-1959; 3; 2 Document Box(es)
  Records in this subseries are arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material and thereunder chronologically.
  Subseries 3, Benevolence Records, provides a useful overview of JDR, Jr.'s charitable giving between 1910 and 1959. Located here is the important Armour report of 1937, detailing contributions made between 1917 and 1936. The memoranda on "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific and Public Contributions..." were first prepared in 1925 and thereafter annually through 1959. They provide retrospective summaries of giving, beginning in 1910.
  - Alexander W. Armour Report on Contributions and Donations of Mr. John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1917-1936, 1937 (Box 46, Folder 434)
  - Correspondence - Dana S. Creel, 1938-1960 (Box 46, Folder 435)
  - Memoranda on Charitable Giving, Covering the Years 1910-1929, 1925-1926 (Box 46, Folder 436)
  - Memoranda on Charitable Giving, Covering the Years 1910-1929, 1928-1929 (Box 46, Folder 437)
  - Memoranda - "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific, and Public Contributions...", 1937-1938 (Box 46, Folder 438)
  - Memoranda - "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific, and Public Contributions...", 1938-1940 (Box 46, Folder 439)
  - Memoranda - "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific, and Public Contributions...", 1941-1942 (Box 46, Folder 440)
  - Memoranda - "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific, and Public Contributions...", 1943-1947 (Box 46, Folder 441)
  - Memoranda - "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific, and Public Contributions...", 1948-1950 (Box 47, Folder 442)
  - Memoranda - "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific, and Public Contributions...", 1951-1954 (Box 47, Folder 443)
  - Memoranda - "Charitable, Educational, Religious, Scientific, and Public Contributions...", 1955-1959 (Box 47, Folder 444)
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Death of John D. Rockefeller, Jr., 1939, 1949-1961; 4; 4 Document Box(es)
  Material in this subseries is arranged alphabetically by subject or type of material and thereunder chronologically.
  Subseries 4, Death of JDR, Jr., includes condolences received by JDR 3rd, Winthrop Rockefeller, and JDR, Jr.'s secretary, Janet Warfield. The subseries contains JDR, Jr.'s will and related correspondence concerning the disposition of his property and works of art.
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (A), 1960 (Box 48, Folder 445)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (B), 1960 (Box 48, Folder 446)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (C-D), 1960 (Box 48, Folder 447)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (E-G), 1960 (Box 48, Folder 448)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (H-I), 1960 (Box 48, Folder 449)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (J-L), 1960 (Box 48, Folder 450)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (M), 1960 (Box 49, Folder 451)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (N-P), 1960 (Box 49, Folder 452)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (Q-R), 1960 (Box 49, Folder 453)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (S), 1960 (Box 49, Folder 454)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (T-V), 1960 (Box 49, Folder 455)
  - Condolences Received by John D. Rockefeller 3rd (W-Z), 1960 (Box 49, Folder 456)
  - Condolences Received by Winthrop Rockefeller, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 457)
  - Condolences Received by Janet Warfield, 1960 (Box 49, Folder 458)
  - Estate (Settlement thereof) - Correspondence, 1960-1961 (Box 50, Folder 459)
    Distribution of works of art to Museums. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Memorial Services - Miscellaneous, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 460)
    Services in National Parks. Correspondents include Laurance S. Rockefeller.
  - Memorial Services - Pocantico Hills, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 461)
    Printed record. Distribution. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Memorial Services - Riverside Church, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 462)
    Notices, order of service, Dr. McCracken's eulogy. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Memorial Services - Riverside Church - Recording, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 463)
  - Memorial Services - Williamsburg, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 464)
    Preparation. Order of service. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Memorials - Suggestions, 1960-1961 (Box 50, Folder 465)
    Various ideas submitted.
  - Publicity, 1960 (Box 50, Folder 466)
    John D. Rockefeller 3rd's letters of thanks to editors. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller 3rd.
  - Sleepy Hollow Grave Sites - Olmsted Brothers, 1939 (Box 50, Folder 467)
  - Tributes, 1960-1961 (Box 50, Folder 468)
    Organizational tributes to John D. Rockefeller, Jr.
  - Will, 1958-1959 (Box 51, Folder 469)
    Memos from John D. Rockefeller, Jr. regarding payments made against pledges in his will. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Phillip Keebler.
  - Will - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 51, Folder 470)
  - Will - Disposition of Works of Art, 1949-1951 (Box 51, Folder 471)
    Discussion of ultimate disposition of tapestries and porcelains. Consideration of Frick Collection or Metropolitan Museum as final depository. Correspondents include John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Thomas M. Debevoise, Frederick Osborn.
- John D. Rockefeller, Jr., Personal Papers - Biographical Works, ca. 1952-1960; 5; 9 Document Box(es)
  Subseries 5, Biographical Works, is arranged alphabetically by author.
  Subseries 5, Biographical Works, mainly documents the research and writing of Raymond B. Fosdick's 1956 biography of JDR, Jr., "John D. Rockefeller, Jr., A Portrait" (New York, Harper & Brothers). In addition to the original typescript manuscript in six volumes, there are 31 volumes of research notebooks. These contain Fosdick's correspondence with JDR, Jr., his staff, and other associates relating to acquiring records documenting JDR, Jr.'s career. The notebooks also comment on the nature of the sources themselves. For example, Fosdick provides valuable descriptions of JDR, Jr.'s correspondence with his father and mother. Included in the notebooks are copies of the correspondence of Mackenzie King, housed in the National Archives of Canada in Ottawa; seven volumes are entirely devoted to the topic of Industrial Relations. Other topics include Organized Religion, Negro Race, Parks, Art, Education, Medicine, Housing, and Variety and Extent of Philanthropic Contributions. Volumes 29-31 contain research reports by M. Pendo, a research assistant.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" (1956) - Manuscript Typescript - Volume 1 (Box 52, Folder 472)
    Foreword The Family Background Boyhood Days College Years
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" (1956) - Manuscript Typescript - Volume 2 (Box 52, Folder 473)
    The Upperclassman 26 Broadway The Maturing Years The Years of Decision
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" (1956) - Manuscript Typescript - Volume 3 (Box 52, Folder 474)
    The Colorado Strike A New Voice in Industrial Relations Father and Son "A Life, Not a Creed"
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" (1956) - Manuscript Typescript - Volume 4 (Box 52, Folder 475)
    The Stewart Case The Eighteenth Amendment Rockefeller Center Williamsburg
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" (1956) - Manuscript Typescript - Volume 5 (Box 52, Folder 476)
    Parks and Conservation "Beauth in the Well-Rounded Life" Restoration Projects
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" (1956) - Manuscript Typescript - Volume 6 (Box 52, Folder 477)
    Education and Research "That Brotherhood May Prevail" "A Life of Crowded Variety" The Man Himself Epilogue Appendix
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 1 (Box 53, Folder 478)
    Notes regarding Files and Equipment Miscellaneous Correspondence - John D. Rockefeller, Jr. Miscellaneous Correspondence - RWG (Ralph Gumbel), etc. Material Returned Cartoons and Photographs
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 2 (Box 53, Folder 479)
    Early Life College Years Early Years in Father's Office General Educational Board
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 3 (Box 53, Folder 480)
    Miscellaneous Colorado Strike 1914-1915, 1921 Industrial Relations Counselors
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 4 (Box 53, Folder 481)
    Industrial Relations (continued) Mackenzie King Correspondence, 1914-1932
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 5 (Box 54, Folder 482)
    Mackenzie King Correspondence, 1930-1951 Welborn-Weitzel-Rockefeller Correspondence, 1915-1922
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 6 (Box 54, Folder 483)
    Mackenzie King Correspondence: Supplement A, 1915-1919, 1923 Supplement B, Ottawa Papers
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 7 (Box 54, Folder 484)
    Three Memoranda on the Colorado Strike, by Mackenzie King.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 8 (Box 54, Folder 485)
    Mackenzie King Correspondence (National Archives of Canada, Ottawa), 1914-1943, vol. 1.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 9 (Box 54, Folder 486)
    Mackenzie King Correspondence (National Archives of Canada, Ottawa), 1914-1943, vol. 2.
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 10 (Box 54, Folder 487)
    International Education Board Stewart Case Restoration Williamsburg Versailles, Rheims, Fontainebleau Philipse Castle, Sunnyside
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 11 (Box 55, Folder 488)
    Organized Religion (Fifth Avenue Baptist Church, Riverside Church) Institute for Social and Religious Research Laymen's Foreign Missions Inquiry
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 12 (Box 55, Folder 489)
    Interdenominational Interests Miscellaneous (Catholic and Jewish Charities and miscellaneous correspondence) Interchurch World Movement Cathedral of St. John the Divine Social and Charitable Organizations Civic Affairs
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 13 (Box 55, Folder 490)
    Negro Race Miscellaneous (Fisk, Tuskegee, Spelman, Hampton, Urban League) International Interests International Houses
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 14 (Box 55, Folder 491)
    Parks General Correspondence Notes on Tilden Manuscript Miscellaneous Parks (Acadia, Mesa Verde, Laboratory of Anthropology, Corkscrew Cypress Sanctuary)
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 15 (Box 55, Folder 492)
    Parks (continued) Fort Tyron Palisades Great Smokies and Shenandoah Save-the-Redwoods League
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 16 (Box 56, Folder 493)
    Parks (continued) Jackson Hole, Wyoming
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 17 (Box 56, Folder 494)
    Art Miscellaneous Material The Agora Cairo Museum The Cloisters
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 18 (Box 56, Folder 495)
    Art (continued) Jerusalem Museum Metropolitan Museum of Art Museum of Modern Art Oriental Institute Frick Museum
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 19 (Box 56, Folder 496)
    Education Miscellaneous I (Acadia, St. Joseph's Normal, Heidelberg, Barnard, MIT) Miscellaneous II (Teachers College, Near East College Association, Library of Congress, New York Public Library) Dartmouth Harvard Seminaries
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 20 (Box 56, Folder 497)
    Education (continued) University of Chicago
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 21 (Box 56, Folder 498)
    Medicine Miscellaneous (Mme. Curie, Bellevue, Insulin, Birth Control) Rockefeller Institute PUMC (Peking Union Medical College) Memorial Hospital Housing
  - Fosdick, Raymond B. - "John D. Rockefeller, Jr.: A Portrait" - Research Notebooks - Volume 22 (Box 57, Folder 499)